Business meetings are, arguably, a necessary part of any organisation where people work collectively to accomplish a goal.
可以说，商务会议是任何组织中的必要组成部分，人们协同工作实现目标。
But badly managed, meetings can be unproductive, boring and feel like a complete waste of time.
但如果管理不善，会议可能会毫无成效、枯燥乏味，感觉完全是浪费时间。
In a recent survey conducted by governance technology firm eShare, it was found that the average UK employee spends over 10 hours weekly preparing for and attending meetings – approximately 50% of which they consider unnecessary.
治理技术公司eShare最近的一项调查发现，英国员工平均每周花在准备和参加会议上的时间超过10小时，其中约50%的会议被认为是不必要的。
However, there are theories that technology could improve things.
不过，有理论认为技术可以改善这种情况。
It's "very feasible" for an AI to be able to recognise when one person is hijacking a meeting, or if a circular discussion keeps returning to a single issue, says James Campanini, from videoconferencing company, BlueJeans.
视频会议公司BlueJeans的詹姆斯・坎帕尼尼表示，人工智能够识别出某人主导会议，或始终循环讨论某个单一问题，这是“完全可以实现的”。
"If no new points are made after a while, the AI could suggest to wrap up," says Cynthia Rudin, a computer science professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
麻省理工学院计算机科学教授辛西娅・鲁丁说：“如果一段时间内没有提出新观点，人工智能可以建议结束会议。”
But AI isn’t quite there yet.
但人工智能尚未完全做到这一点。
"If AI can do most of the mundane and drudgery work during business meetings, that leaves more space for humans to think about strategy and vision," believes Niki Iliadis at the Big Innovation centre, London, an innovation hub in AI.
伦敦人工智能创新中心“大创新中心”的尼基・伊利亚季斯认为：“如果人工智能能承担商务会议中大部分mundane（单调乏味的）和drudgery（繁重乏味的）工作，就能为人类腾出更多空间思考战略和愿景。”
This seems to be true.
这似乎是事实。
The prefecture of Osaka in Japan started using an AI as a minute taker to transcribe and summarise the 450 annual cabinet meetings.
日本大阪府已开始使用人工智能作为会议记录员，转录和总结每年450次的内阁会议。
It has halved the time needed to produce summaries and cut staff overtime, claims the prefecture.
该府称，这将生成会议纪要的时间缩短了一半，并减少了员工加班。
AI can also help with the matter of attendance.
人工智能还可以帮助解决出勤问题。
If a meeting with irrelevant subject matter is called, or if it's an an inconvenient time, an AI could be used to decide who should attend the meeting and when it should be, says Elise Keith from Lucid Meetings, a US-based meeting management platform.
美国会议管理平台Lucid Meetings的伊莉斯・基思表示，如果会议主题无关紧要，或者时间不合适，人工智能可以用来决定谁该参加会议以及何时召开会议。
Finally, one Stockholm start-up, Mentimeter, allows meeting attendees to give anonymous feedback about a discussion.
最后，斯德哥尔摩的一家初创公司Mentimeter允许参会者对讨论给出匿名反馈。
Using the software, participants can make open-ended responses, submit comments or vote in multiple-choice quizzes.
使用该软件，参与者可以做出开放式回答、提交评论或在多项选择测试中投票。
This has "fundamentally changed the dynamics of a presentation," says Austin Broad from financial services firm AFH Wealth Management.
金融服务公司AFH Wealth Management的奥斯汀・布罗德表示，这“从根本上改变了会议的动态变化”。
While tools that can create agendas, send meeting invitations, distribute the minutes, and keep track of action items should improve effectiveness, they are still in development.
虽然可以创建议程、发送会议邀请、分发会议纪要和跟踪待办事项的工具应该能提高效率，但它们仍在开发中。
Let's hope that if or when they do arrive, they will meet our expectations.
我们希望，如果这些工具最终问世，能够符合我们的期望。